Mary Donovan Martello

5107 Jackson Street, Omaha, NE 68106 Phone: (402) 305-4633 E-mail: mdonovanmartello@gmail.com

Profile

I was a lawyer and a CPA for 26 years, but I earned a Master's in Data Science through Bellevue University in June of 2021. I also have completed a COBOL class through AIM Code School (f/k/a Interface, the Web School) and a front-end web development class through the Midland University Code Academy. I also volunteer as a teaching assistant for Mystery Code Society.

Objective

To obtain a full-time data scientist position utilizing my analytical, problem-solving, programming and statistical skills.

Portfolio: https://marydonovanmartello.github.io/

Highlighted skills and knowledge include:

- Python and R
- Data mining
- Predictive analytics
- Data wrangling and exploration
- Deep learning
- Data Visualization
- Statistics
- COBOL
- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript

- Accounting/financial/ tax analysis
- Writing and speaking skills
- Research
- Excel spreadsheets

Experience

Self-Employed – Estate and Business Planning Attorney

- Negotiated advantageous million dollar IRS settlement
- Guided multi-million dollar charitable foundation through transitions and plan for termination
- Resolved issues with entity accountings and reports
- Designed adjustment to estate plans for tax law changes

Dvorak & Donovan Law Group, LLC Equity Partner Attorney – Estate & Business Planning

- Efficiently transitioned significant client base to new firm
- Successfully structured financial/business aspects of firm
- Led estate planning and administration practice
- Designed multi-millions tax, estate and business plans
- Trained and developed attorneys

February 2017 - Present

January 2015 – February 2017

Resume: Mary Donovan Martello

August 1999 - January 2015

March 1998 - August 1999

Koley Jessen, P.C. L.L.O.

Attorney - Estate and Business Planning

Equity Partner/Associate Attorney

- Provided highest quality of legal and tax counsel
- Designed plans for multi-million estates/businesses
- Successfully guided and settled complex estates
- Research and resolved complicated issues
- Trained and developed attorneys/paralegals

Nelson, Morrow & Waldron Law Office Attorney – Estate and Business Planning

• Developed expertise as tax and estate attorney

Coopers & Lybrand L.L.P. (National Accounting Firm) September 1995 – April 1998 Certified Public Accountant

• Obtained a Certified Public Accountant license

Education

Bellevue University, Bellevue, Nebraska
Master's in Data Science Candidate
Nov 2019 – June 2021
Nov 2018 – Feb 2019
Business Analytics Certificate
GPA: 4.0

Python, R Programming, EDA, Data Mining, Predictive Analytics

AIM Institute/Interface: The Web School, Omaha, Nebraska Interface COBOL Course COBOL

Midland University Code Academy, Omaha, Nebraska Web Foundations HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and JavaScript

Creighton University School of Law, Omaha, Nebraska Juris Doctor

Emphasis on tax and estate planning courses

Creighton University – College of Business, Omaha, Nebraska Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

Business/Law Accelerated Program – Emphasis on accounting courses

Volunteer Activity

- Mystery Code Society (Teaching Assistant)
- Coalition on Human Trafficking
- Omaha Morning Rotary (Past President /Treasurer)
- Former TeamMates Mentor

Sept – Dec 2018

May – August 2018

May 1995 Magna Cum Laude

Class rank: 9/155

May 1993 Summa Cum Laude

GPA: 4.0